<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travels on James Blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travels on James Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jamesblogger.com/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switzerland Free Travel | 4-Day Immersive Journey into the Alpine Wonderland – From Lakes to Snowy Peaks</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Switzerland-20240914/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Switzerland-20240914/</guid>
      <description>Switzerland is undoubtedly one of the most expensive places in the world. I originally thought the Netherlands and the UK were already pricey, but the cost of living here feels almost 1.5 to 2 times higher than those areas. Despite this, Switzerland remains my favorite country so far. When I used to hear about Switzerland, a few keywords always came up – wealthy people, watches, the Alps, and stunning nature. This time, I finally got to experience it firsthand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England - Two Days in London 20240906</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/London-20240906/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/London-20240906/</guid>
      <description>London is a city I might have known about since I was three years old, but I had never been there. For big cities like this, I only knew a few keywords – like the &amp;ldquo;foggy city,&amp;rdquo; Big Ben, and London Bridge. This time, I was thrilled to finally have the chance to visit and wander around. However, London has so many places to visit that two days really isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to see much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany - Three Days in Munich 20240823</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Munich-20240823/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Munich-20240823/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 We took a Flixbus overnight from Eindhoven to Munich, a trip that took more than 10 hours. Besides being cheap, there aren’t many perks to this kind of journey—sleeping upright in a seat and not being able to stretch your legs is tough, and then having to start exploring right after arriving is even tougher. But, at least we saved two nights&amp;rsquo; worth of accommodation costs, which is great because otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;d be broke.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belgium - Ghent &amp; Brussels Day Trip 20240728</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/ghent-20240728/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/ghent-20240728/</guid>
      <description>Ghent I spent just one day in Ghent, primarily for their music festival. The Ghent Festival runs for only 10 days each year. Although there isn’t much information online, the official website lists various activities and parades. We skipped those and instead explored the city&amp;rsquo;s main sights while soaking in the festival vibe.&#xA;We took a Flixbus to Brussels and then a train to Ghent.&#xA;Sint-Bassfskathedraal You can only climb this cathedral during the Ghent Festival, and it costs just €2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netherlands - A Day Trip to Den Haag 20240720</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Den-Haag-20240810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Den-Haag-20240810/</guid>
      <description>This trip was all about heading to the beach, so we didn’t visit many places. I originally planned to go next week, but suddenly noticed that the weather was fantastic this weekend, with temperatures around 30°C. The weather in the Netherlands changes quickly, and good weather doesn’t last long, so I decided to seize the day and head out.&#xA;I won&amp;rsquo;t go into details about transportation, as I&amp;rsquo;m staying in the Netherlands for six months and have already bought an OV card with a weekend free plan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belgium - Two-Day Trip to Bruges 2024/07/13</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/bruges-20240713/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/bruges-20240713/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 We took a Flixbus from Eindhoven to Brussels and then a train to Bruges. For trains in Belgium, you need to buy a ticket, but for buses, you can just use a credit card to pay directly. Here are two detailed travel guides I found super helpful. However, the transportation here is quite simple—Google Maps will</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Day Trip to Paris - 2024-01-25</title>
      <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/paris-20240125/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/paris-20240125/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 My first solo trip was to Europe, and the moment I got off the plane, everything felt new. Standing in a foreign city, surrounded by an unfamiliar environment and language, the word &amp;ldquo;unknown&amp;rdquo; defined our entire journey. No matter how well-prepared we were, exploring a new country and culture always brings unexpected surprises and insights. The main takeaway from this trip was experiencing these cities firsthand, not just for the attractions, but also for their overall atmosphere and culture.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
