<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Travel - category - James Blog</title>
        <link>https://jamesblogger.com/categories/Travel/</link>
        <description>Travel - category - James Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesblogger.com/categories/Travel/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>England - Two Days in London 20240906</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/London-20240906/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/London-20240906/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[London is a city I might have known about since I was three years old, but I had never been there. For big cities like this, I only knew a few keywords – like the &ldquo;foggy city,&rdquo; Big Ben, and London Bridge. This time, I was thrilled to finally have the chance to visit and wander around. However, London has so many places to visit that two days really isn&rsquo;t enough to see much.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Germany - Three Days in Munich 20240823</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Munich-20240823/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Munich-20240823/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Day 1 We took a Flixbus overnight from Eindhoven to Munich, a trip that took more than 10 hours. Besides being cheap, there aren’t many perks to this kind of journey—sleeping upright in a seat and not being able to stretch your legs is tough, and then having to start exploring right after arriving is even tougher. But, at least we saved two nights&rsquo; worth of accommodation costs, which is great because otherwise, I&rsquo;d be broke.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Belgium - Ghent &amp; Brussels Day Trip 20240728</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/ghent-20240728/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/ghent-20240728/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ghent I spent just one day in Ghent, primarily for their music festival. The Ghent Festival runs for only 10 days each year. Although there isn’t much information online, the official website lists various activities and parades. We skipped those and instead explored the city&rsquo;s main sights while soaking in the festival vibe.
We took a Flixbus to Brussels and then a train to Ghent.
Sint-Bassfskathedraal You can only climb this cathedral during the Ghent Festival, and it costs just €2.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Netherlands - A Day Trip to Den Haag 20240720</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Den-Haag-20240810/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/Den-Haag-20240810/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This trip was all about heading to the beach, so we didn’t visit many places. I originally planned to go next week, but suddenly noticed that the weather was fantastic this weekend, with temperatures around 30°C. The weather in the Netherlands changes quickly, and good weather doesn’t last long, so I decided to seize the day and head out.
I won&rsquo;t go into details about transportation, as I&rsquo;m staying in the Netherlands for six months and have already bought an OV card with a weekend free plan.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Belgium - Two-Day Trip to Bruges 2024/07/13</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/bruges-20240713/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/travel/bruges-20240713/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Day 1 We took a Flixbus from Eindhoven to Brussels and then a train to Bruges. For trains in Belgium, you need to buy a ticket, but for buses, you can just use a credit card to pay directly. Here are two detailed travel guides I found super helpful. However, the transportation here is quite simple—Google Maps will]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
