<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Sliding Window - tag - James Blog</title>
        <link>https://jamesblogger.com/tags/Sliding-Window/</link>
        <description>Sliding Window - tag - James Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesblogger.com/tags/Sliding-Window/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>[ Leetcode 1343 ] Number of Sub-arrays of Size K and Average Greater than or Equal to Threshold | Solution Approach &amp; Explanation</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/program/leetcode-1343/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/program/leetcode-1343/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Given an integer array nums, along with two integers k and threshold, find the number of subarrays of length k whose average is greater than or equal to threshold.
Link🔗：https://leetcode.com/problems/number-of-sub-arrays-of-size-k-and-average-greater-than-or-equal-to-threshold/
Problem Analysis The goal is to find all subarrays of length k that meet the given condition. This means we need to examine every subarray of length k.
Brute Force A straightforward approach is to enumerate all possible subarrays of length k.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>[ Leetcode 3 ] Longest Substring Without Repeating Characters | Solution Approach &amp; Explanation</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/program/leetcode-3/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/program/leetcode-3/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Given a string s, find the length of the longest substring without repeating characters.
Link🔗：https://leetcode.com/problems/longest-substring-without-repeating-characters/
Problem Analysis The objective is to find the longest substring without repeating characters, meaning we must examine every possible substring.
Brute Force The most straightforward brute-force approach is to enumerate all possible substrings and check for repeated characters. However, this results in a time complexity of O(n²), which is too slow and will cause time limit exceeded (TLE) errors.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>[ Leetcode 209 ] Minimum Size Subarray Sum | Solution Approach &amp; Explanation</title>
    <link>https://jamesblogger.com/program/leetcode-209/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>James</name>
    </author><guid>https://jamesblogger.com/program/leetcode-209/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Given a positive integer array nums and a target value target, find the smallest contiguous subarray whose sum is greater than or equal to target. If no such subarray exists, return 0.
Link🔗：https://leetcode.com/problems/minimum-size-subarray-sum/
Method 1 - Sliding Window This problem can be solved using the Sliding Window technique. Since all numbers in the array are positive, we know that if a subarray sum reaches or exceeds target, adding more numbers will only make it longer but won&rsquo;t help find the shortest subarray.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
